[
    {
        "question": "What is India's rank in the recently released 2025 Henley Passport Index?",
        "options": [
            "85 ",
            "80 ",
            "86 ",
            "82 "
        ],
        "answer": "85 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the 2025 Henley Passport Index, which country\u2019s passport is the most powerful in the world?",
        "options": [
            "Singapore ",
            "Japan ",
            "France  ",
            "Germany "
        ],
        "answer": "Singapore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the recently released 2025 Henley Passport Index, an Indian passport holder can visit visa-free to how many countries in the world?",
        "options": [
            "58 ",
            "57 ",
            "76 ",
            "45 "
        ],
        "answer": "57 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was ranked at the bottom of the 2025 Henley Passport Index?",
        "options": [
            "Iraq ",
            "Afghanistan ",
            "Yemen ",
            "Syria "
        ],
        "answer": "Afghanistan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chairman cum Managing Director of National Aluminium Company Limited (NALCO)?",
        "options": [
            "Sunil Kumar Gupta ",
            "Brijendra Pratap Singh ",
            "Vivek Mehrotra ",
            "Hirdyesh Mohan "
        ],
        "answer": "Brijendra Pratap Singh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total issue size announced by Edelweiss Financial Services Limited (EFSL) for its public Non-Convertible Debentures (NCDs) issue?",
        "options": [
            "Rs. 1,000 million ",
            "Rs. 1,500 million ",
            "Rs. 2,000 million ",
            "Rs. 2,500 million "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs. 2,000 million ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which regulatory body lifted the supervisory restrictions on Asirvad Micro Finance Limited and DMI Finance Private Limited?",
        "options": [
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "IRDAI ",
            "NABARD "
        ],
        "answer": "RBI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has Bank of Baroda partnered with for its upgraded Employee Assistance Program (EAP)?",
        "options": [
            "Truworth Wellness ",
            "Fortis Healthcare ",
            "LIC of India ",
            "Tata Health "
        ],
        "answer": "Truworth Wellness ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has officially joined the BRICS as a full member in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Singapore ",
            "Mauritius ",
            "Indonesia ",
            "Malaysia "
        ],
        "answer": "Indonesia ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country will hold the 17th Summit meeting of BRICS in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Brazil  ",
            "Russia  ",
            "China ",
            "South Africa "
        ],
        "answer": "Brazil  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a BRICS country?",
        "options": [
            "UAE ",
            "Egypt  ",
            "Ethiopia  ",
            "Argentina "
        ],
        "answer": "Argentina ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018Anji Khad Bridge\u2019, recently seen in the news, is located in:",
        "options": [
            "Arunachal Pradesh ",
            "Assam ",
            "Jammu and Kashmir ",
            "Uttarakhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Jammu and Kashmir ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding \u2018Z-Morh Tunnel\u2019, recently seen in the news:  1. It is a 2-lane railway tunnel in located in Jammu and Kashmir.  2. It is vital for ensuring year-round connectivity to Ladakh.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "2 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding \u2018AnemiaPhone\u2019, recently seen in the news:  1. It is a technology developed by the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR).  2. It helps to assess iron deficiency which is a leading cause of anemia.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "2 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "'The Future of Jobs Report 2025' has been released by which organisation?",
        "options": [
            "World Economic Forum (WEF) ",
            "World Bank (WB) ",
            "International Monetary Fund (IMF) D) United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) "
        ],
        "answer": "Unknown",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the \u2018EmpowHER Biz\u2019 initiative:  1. It offers mentorship and comprehensive training to aspiring women entrepreneurs.  2. It is an initiative of the Union Ministry of Women and Child Development.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes \u2018Garudakshi\u2019, recently seen in the news?",
        "options": [
            "It is software modelled on the online FIR system to curb wildlife and forests crime. ",
            "It is a new AI tool to monitor transactions through darknet ",
            "It is an initiative to build diesel-electric submarines for the Indian Navy ",
            "It is an online platform to monitor biomagnification of pesticides like DDT for the decline of eagle "
        ],
        "answer": "It is software modelled on the online FIR system to curb wildlife and forests crime. ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding \u2018Pravasi Bharatiya Divas\u2019:  1. It is a flagship event of the Ministry of External Affairs.  2. It is held on January 9th to commemorate the return of Mahatma Gandhi from South Africa.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Portal has been launched by the government of India to make the genome data accessible to researchers under the GenomeIndia Project?",
        "options": [
            "Biodiversity Heritage Library Portal ",
            "Biomarker Insights Portal ",
            "UniProt knowledgebase Portal  ",
            "Indian Biological Data Centre  Portal "
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Biological Data Centre  Portal ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who inaugurated India\u2019s first national repository for life science data, the Indian Biological Data Centre?",
        "options": [
            "Narendra Modi  ",
            "Draupadi Murmu  ",
            "Jitendra Singh ",
            "Amit Shah "
        ],
        "answer": "Jitendra Singh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been elected as the President of Lebanon?",
        "options": [
            "Joseph Aoun ",
            "Ziad Baroud ",
            "Elias Murr ",
            "Ghazi Aridi "
        ],
        "answer": "Joseph Aoun ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1020 MW Punatsangchhu-II Hydroelectric Project is being developed in which country?",
        "options": [
            "Nepal  ",
            "Afghanistan  ",
            "Bangladesh  ",
            "Bhutan "
        ],
        "answer": "Bhutan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 8th edition of the Indusfood trade exhibition held?",
        "options": [
            "Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Guwahati, Assam  ",
            "Bhubaneswar, Odisha  ",
            "Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has achieved \u2018Excellent\u2019 rating for the performance MoU signed with the Ministry of New & Renewable Energy (MNRE) for the financial year 2023-24, with a score of 98.24.?",
        "options": [
            "NTPC  ",
            "IREDA ",
            "BHEL ",
            "GAIL "
        ],
        "answer": "IREDA ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the projected GDP growth rate for India in the fiscal year 2024-25 as per the first advance estimates?",
        "options": [
            "6.4% ",
            "6.8% ",
            "7.2% ",
            "6.6% "
        ],
        "answer": "6.4% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Deputy Managing Director and Group Chief Risk Officer of State Bank of India?",
        "options": [
            "Baldev Prakash ",
            "Ashwini Kumar Tewari ",
            "Vinay M. Tonse ",
            "Rama Mohan Rao Amara "
        ],
        "answer": "Baldev Prakash ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the singles title of the women\u2019s Under 17 British Junior Open Squash Tournament 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Anahat Singh ",
            "Malika Elkaraksy ",
            "Ruqayya Salem ",
            "Nadia Tamer "
        ],
        "answer": "Anahat Singh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anahat Singh who was in the news recently belongs to which sports?",
        "options": [
            "Badminton  ",
            "Tennis  ",
            "Squash ",
            "Football "
        ],
        "answer": "Squash ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company is setting up India\u2019s first Green Hydrogen Hub project under the National Green Hydrogen Mission?",
        "options": [
            "JSW Energy Ltd ",
            "Adani Green Energy Ltd ",
            "Adani New Industries Limited ",
            "NTPC Green Hydrogen Limited "
        ],
        "answer": "NTPC Green Hydrogen Limited ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who laid the foundation stone of India\u2019s first Green Hydrogen Hub project under the National Green Hydrogen Mission in Andhra Pradesh?",
        "options": [
            "Draupadi Murmu  ",
            "Amit Shah  ",
            "N.Chandrababau Naidu ",
            "Narendra Modi "
        ],
        "answer": "Narendra Modi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "As per Union Budget 2025-26, The central government is likely to increase the borrowing limit under the Kisan Credit Card (KCC) scheme from Rs 3 lakh to Rs ?",
        "options": [
            "scheme from Rs 3 lakh to Rs ? ",
            "\u20b95 lakh ",
            "\u20b94 lakh ",
            "\u20b93.5 lakh ",
            "\u20b94.5 lakh "
        ],
        "answer": "scheme from Rs 3 lakh to Rs ? ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which digital payment app has partnered with ICICI Lombard General Insurance to offer insurance cover for people travelling to the Maha Kumbh Mela in Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh?",
        "options": [
            "Paytm ",
            "Google Pay ",
            "PhonePe ",
            "MobiKwik "
        ],
        "answer": "PhonePe ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which companies has unveiled a series of AI-driven strategic partnerships with the Government of India?",
        "options": [
            "Apple  ",
            "Microsoft  ",
            "Amazon  ",
            "Google "
        ],
        "answer": "Microsoft  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity and IIMA Ventures has launched Swanari TechSprint 3.0, a programme aimed at fostering women-centric fintech startups in India?",
        "options": [
            "Reserve Bank Innovation Hub (RBIH) ",
            "Deposit Insurance and Credit Guarantee Corporation of India (DICGC)  ",
            "Reserve Bank Information Technology Private Limited (ReBIT) ",
            "Indian Financial Technology and Allied Services (IFTAS) "
        ],
        "answer": "Reserve Bank Innovation Hub (RBIH) ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which food delivery giant has launched a standalone app for quick commerce arm Instamart?",
        "options": [
            "Zomato ",
            "Swiggy ",
            "Foodpanda ",
            "Domino's Pizza "
        ],
        "answer": "Swiggy ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]